《絕命律師》前情回顧
Previously on "Better Call Saul"
你可以接自己的案子
You'd be working on your case.
查克不會同意的
Chuck wouldn't like it.
查克管不著
Chuck has no say in this.
剛剛和你做的這筆生意
This deal he's doing with you,
他是背著同伙做的
he's doing outside his crew.
他可不想被他老大發現
He doesn't want his bosses to know.
我之前有一套棒球卡片的珍藏
I had a baseball card collection--
全沒了
All gone!
你確定他們不是在找其他東西嗎
You're sure they weren't looking for anything else?
如果我們每晚都那樣  不是很好嗎
Wouldn't it be great if we could do that every night?
是啊  但我們不能那樣
Yes, but we can't.
我們本可以每人帶八十萬美金回家  不用交稅
We could have gone home with $800,000, tax free!
你想說什么
Your point being?
我們為什么沒那么干
Why didn't we?
這位是詹姆斯·麥吉爾
James McGill.
這位是克利福德·梅因
Clifford Main.
叫我吉米就好
Just Jimmy.
《西西里舞曲》  弗雷作曲
麗貝卡·博伊斯
-霍華德  -早上好
- Howard. - Morning!
有麥吉爾的東西
Delivery for McGill.
你來這兒干什么
What're you doing here?
咱倆有一陣沒見了
Ah, it's been a while.
我覺得我應該過來看看你
Thought I should come in and check on you.
我剛才好像聽到音樂了
Did I hear music?
沒  我剛才在...  我幫你拿吧
No, no. I was just -- ‭let me get that for you.
-見到你真好  霍華德  -我也很高興
- Good to see you, Howard. - Oh, likewise.
大家都非常想你  朋友
You are sorely missed, my friend.
別把這當負擔
Don't take that as any undue pressure.
我在考慮  下星期過去待一兩個小時
Um, I'm thinking of maybe coming in for an hour or two next week.
隨機應變就行
Maybe kind of play it by ear.
如果你愿意的話
Well, ‭i-if you feel comfortable.
我們當然很歡迎你
I mean, we certainly would love to have you.
我們什么都能接受
We will take anything we can get.
日子定了我讓歐內斯托提前通知你們一聲
I'll figure out a day and get Ernesto to give you a heads up.
不錯
That sounds great.
歐尼近來如何
How's Ernie working out?
大體上說  還不錯
Uh, he's been fine, for the most part.
太棒了
Excellent.
磯鷂渡一案  一切正常嗎
Everything on track with, uh, Sandpiper?
正在進行
Moving along.
戴維斯梅因律所真的很盡力
Davis & Main are, uh... really pulling their weight.
他們最好盡力
Well, they better.
案子很復雜
It's a complex case.
這案子肯定不是兩個人就能搞定的
Well, it's definitely not a two-man job, that's for sure.
誰有吉米的消息嗎
Anyone, uh, heard from Jimmy?
我有  我跟他談過
I have, yes. I've talked to him.
他怎么樣
How is he?
他很好
He's fine.
還不錯
Doing well.
說到他  我有些消息
Speaking of which... I have some news.
他在戴維斯梅因律所工作
He's working at Davis & Main.
做什么
Doing what?
是做律師啊
Oh, working as an attorney.
克利福德·梅因雇了吉米
Clifford Main hired Jimmy?
說實話  他也有疑慮
To be fair, he had his doubts,
但他給了吉米一個機會
but he's giving Jimmy a chance.
他派自己的手下去跟客戶聯系
He had his own people doing client outreach,
但他們每次和磯鷂渡的居住者談話
but every time they would talk to a Sandpiper resident,
住戶就會讓吉米出馬
Jimmy's name would come up.
你知道的  他
You know, he...
-那些老人  他們  -他們喜歡他
- Those old folks, they just -- - They love him.
的確是
Yeah, they do.
另外  我猜克利福德希望
Plus, I guess Cliff thought it would be a good idea
案子有那種...
for the case to have that sort of, uh...
連續性
you know... continuity.
吉米待人處事有一套
Jimmy certainly has a way with people.
是啊
He does.
戴維斯梅因律所知道他的背景嗎
They're aware of his background at Davis & Main?
他的教育情況
His education?
不瞞你說
In the spirit of full disclosure,
克利福徳之前確實跟我談過
Cliff did talk to me beforehand.
我都實話跟他說了
I didn't pull any punches.
我盡可能客觀地跟他說
I tried to paint a complete picture.
但我沒有礙事
But I didn't stand in the way.
當然了
Of course not.
你也不應該礙事
Nor should you.
說實話
Truth be told...
金·韋克斯勒為此事極力爭取
Kim Wexler pushed for this -- hard.
但我沒礙事
But I didn't, uh, you know, stand in the way.
合伙人機會
Partner track?
我會
I would, uh...
對
Yeah.
我想是吧
Assume so.
真不錯
That's great.
吉米不錯啊
Good for Jimmy.
-騙子查理  對嗎  -對
- Charlie Hustle, right? - Yep.
對
‭Yep.
那我不打擾你了
Well, I'll get out of your hair.
還需要我往歐尼的單子上加點別的嗎
Anything else you need me to add to Ernie's list?
不用  都有了
No. All set. All good.
謝謝你過來  霍華德
Thanks for coming by, Howard.
不用謝  我們真的很想你
Any time. You truly are missed.
別有壓力
No pressure.
絕命律師
第二季 第二集
翻譯  杏仁斯嘉麗 喵球球 joy_bwl 人妻
翻譯  克里斯 肉松 西陵折枝 自然卷
校對  喃喃
時間軸  夢龍 姜姜
金柏莉·韋克斯勒
后期  潤天使小新     總監  喃喃
法蘭西斯·雪夫
文件審查由哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所負責協調
Document review will be coordinated through HHM.
詹姆斯·麥吉爾
目前  已經向磯鷂渡請求獲取以下文件
To date, the following documents have been requested from Sandpiper
并作為首次披露申請書的一部分
as part of our initial discovery petition.
一  磯鷂渡所有分部迄今為止的
One -- resident lease agreements, past and present,
居住者租賃協議
from all Sandpiper locations.
二  磯鷂渡全部供應商的
Two -- invoices and transaction documents
發票和交易憑證
from all supply companies used by Sandpiper.
三  磯鷂渡迄今為止所有正式賣主的名單
Three -- list of all past and present official Sandpiper vendors.
四  磯鷂渡與經銷商的
Four -- any and all business agreements and contracts
全部業務協議和合同
between Sandpiper and its distributors.
五  居住者社保收據記錄
Five -- records of residents' social security check receipts.
六  津貼交易結算清單
Six -- allowance transaction statements.
七  居住者的無關發票...
Seven -- resident invoices non-related to sup--
我喜歡新造型
I'm loving the new look.
圣達菲怎么樣
How's Santa Fe?
真...
It's, uh --
真的還...
It's -- it's really...
看  我跟你說了
See? What'd I tell you?
地方不錯吧
Nice place? ‭
公司臨租房中最好的
The finest in temporary corporate housing.
迫不及待想看了
Can't wait to see it.
也許我該離開哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所
Maybe I should leave HHM.
登上戴維斯梅因的賺錢快車
Get on that cushy D&M train.
賺得又多又快
It is very cushy.
棒極了
It's amazing.
吉米...
Jimmy...
我很為你高興
I'm so happy for you.
謝謝
Thanks.
情況大有好轉
You know, things are really turning around.
我甚至考慮
I'm even thinking of looking, you know,
買自己的房子
my own place to buy.
-在圣達菲嗎  -還不確定
- In Santa Fe? - ‭Not sure yet.
也許是離阿爾布開克更近的地方
Maybe someplace, uh, closer to Albuquerque
因為我得經常兩頭跑
since I'm going between the two so much.
好吧
Okay.
那就兩地中間咯
So, halfway points.
我在想...
Yeah, I was thinking, uh...
最新美劇下載
-等等  科拉萊斯怎么樣  -科拉萊斯
- Oh, wait, what about Corrales? - Corrales.
找個精致的小別墅
Yeah, get a nice, little bungalow,
大點也行
or maybe not so little.
平面設計寬敞開闊
Big, open floor plan.
我不希望墻壁擾亂我的氣  沒錯
I don't want any walls disrupting my chi, yeah.
我確實覺得要塊大地皮
Uh, but I'm thinking I definitely want some decent acreage,
可以接觸自然
get in touch with nature.
馬
Horses.
沒錯  你可以養馬
Come on. You could get horses.
天  簡單太棒了
Man, that would be so amazing.
太貴了  只吃燕麥  對吧
Too expensive. ‭They, uh, all the oats -- right?
它們都吃燕麥吧
It's oats ‭that they're always eating?
-很值  -還有馬蹄鐵
- It's worth it. - ‭And the horseshoes.
你得給它們用錘子裝備好"鞋"
You have to get them shoes and nail them with a hammer.
非常值...
It's totally worth it. It's --
在鄉間騎馬散步
Long ride through the country
后院一杯酒  看夕陽西下
and then glass of wine on the back patio at sunset.
我們該買個烤肉機
Oh, we should get one of those smokers.
輕輕松松烤幾天肉
We could just barbecue for days.
沒錯  我們真該買一個
Yeah. We definitely got to get a smoker.
好吧...
All right, well...
我得去美甲店了
I got to go to the salon.
他們要運來我嶄新的公司用車
They're delivering my new company car.
真的嗎
Ugh, are you serious?
怎么
What? ‭
小說人物  指理想聰明的男仆
吉夫斯  我的純金飛艇在哪兒
Jeeves, ‭where's my solid-gold blimp?
不  不是那輛  另一輛
No, not that one. The other one.
嫉妒
Jealous.
好嫉妒哦
Totally.
我忘了  我給你買了個禮物  等會兒
Oh, I forgot. ‭I got you a present. One sec.
包裝真精美
‭Such a beautiful wrapping job.
都不忍打開
It's a shame to open it.
這是禮物  別嘴欠
It's a gift. Be grateful.
世上第二棒的律師
保持真我
Just keeping it real.
別氣餒
Come on.
第二已經非常棒了
Second is still very, very good.
好吧
All right.
謝謝
Thanks.
今晚見嗎
See you tonight?
再說
Maybe.
如果你表現好的話
If you play your cards right.
你好啊美女
Hello, beautiful.
女士們  喜歡嗎
What do you think, ladies?
我知道  很棒吧
Yeah, I know, right?
內部全真皮
It's got all leather interior,
加熱座椅適合沙漠地區寒冷的早晨
heated seats for those cold desert mornings.
這絕對是天堂的樣子
This must be what heaven looks like.
來個告別擁抱吧
Goodbye hug?
不來嗎
No?
好吧  那就擦干淚水
All right, well, forgo the tears
輕輕說一句  后會有期
and just say, "Till we meet again."
大概是公制尺寸的吧
Must be metric.
沃爾多峽谷路
拉謝內加
圣達菲
你在這干什么
What -- what are you doing here?
我在這兒工作
I work here.
真巧啊
Small world.
那這里是警局的停車場嗎
So, is this the parking lot for the police station?
是的
It is.
你不知道他們能不能讓我進  對吧
You don't know if they validate, do you?
不如你在那邊停車吧
Why don't you pull around over there,
我們談幾句
and we'll have a little talk.
好吧
Uh, okay.
你來這干什么
Why are you here?
我有事找警察
I-I have business with the police.
是什么事呢
And what business might that be?
如果你非要知道的話  我被搶劫了
Well, if you must know, I was robbed.
有人闖進我家  偷走了我的財產
Somebody broke into my house and stole my property.
你的毒品吧
Your drugs.
是的  但顯然我沒對警察說
Yeah, but obviously I didn't tell the cops that.
我又不蠢
I'm not stupid.
你已經和他們說過情況了嗎
You've already spoken to them?
兩個警察來過我家
A couple of them came by my house.
但我在意的不是毒品
But it's not the drugs that I care about.
不  我在意
I mean, I care.
但我更想討回我的棒球卡片
It's my baseball cards I need back.
-你的棒球卡片  -是的
- Your baseball cards? ‭- Yes.
我有一套非常珍貴的棒球卡片集
I have a very valuable collection of baseball cards,
被人偷走了
and someone stole them.
我就知道還得我來跟你說
I guess I shouldn't be surprised I have to tell you this.
你已經是個罪犯了  還主動找警察談話
But it's probably a bad idea that you willingly talk to the police,
這大概不是個好主意
being a criminal and all.
我又不是以罪犯的身份來的
I'm not here as a criminal.
我是受害者
I'm here as a crime victim.
我只是偶爾賣賣藥品
Just because I occasionally sell some pharmaceuticals,
就要失去受法律保護的權利嗎
I no longer have a right to protection from crime?
而且我和他們談的時候非常謹慎
And I was very careful when I talked to them.
他們不知道我賣藥
I -- they have no idea about my other business.
既然你已經報告過情況了  為什么還要來
If you already made your report, why are you here?
他們喊我來的
They called me.
說還有幾個問題要問
They have a few more questions.
他們很努力地在尋找小偷
They are very dedicated to finding this thief.
既然你還是個新手  我來給你解釋一下
Since you're new to this, let me explain it to you.
他們在釣魚
They've invited you on a fishing trip.
什么意思  釣魚
What's that? A fishing trip?
那些警察對討回你的卡片根本沒興趣
Those cops have no interest in helping you get your cards back.
他們顯然懷疑你
You're obviously under suspicion.
他們什么也沒看到啊
There was nothing there for them to see.
你想想我們之前的談話
I refer you ‭to our previous conversation
再看看這個如霓虹燈般閃閃發光的
and this blinking neon sign of a vehicle
寫滿"毒販子"三個字的車
that says "Drug dealer."
他們懷疑你
They suspect you.
他們會讓你進去  裝作是你的朋友
They will get you in there, pretend to be your friend,
給你一種虛假的安全感
lull you into a false sense of security,
然后他們會讓你心虛
and then they will sweat you.
你就會露出破綻
and you will break.
我不  我
I don't -- I --
我不同意
I disagree.
沒有商量的余地  你現在就回家
Not open for debate. You go home now.
但是我和他們約好了啊
But I have an appointment.
爽約
Break it.
如果他們打電話給你  別接
And if they call you, do not answer the phone.
那我的棒球卡片怎么辦
But what about my baseball cards?
那是你生意的代價
Cost of doing business.
不行  不不不
No! No, no, no!
我得討回來
I am getting those back!
我愿意冒險
I will take the risk!
不  你不能冒險
No, you won't.
因為你會把我也置于險境
Because then you'll be putting my well-being at risk.
我只能這樣
I have to!
我  我
I-I --
那些卡片啊
Those cards?
有一部分是我爸留給我的
Some of them were my dad's.
我要討回來
I-I am getting them back.
我必須討回來
I'm getting them back.
我會找到你的卡片的
I'll find your cards.
先生  你
Is -- sir--
你也能做這個嗎
Is that something you do?
那真是
Wow, that's...
那你真是太好了
That is so generous of you.
你要付我錢的
Oh, it'll cost you.
好吧
Okay, uh...
我們可以討論下財務問題
We should discuss some sort of financial arrangement
我可以...
in which I-I, uh...
那好吧
Okay, then!
老天
Jesus.
戴維斯梅因律所
律師
保證金
磯鷂渡生活協助中心
居住合同
請進
Come on in.
我不是故意打斷你的
I didn't mean to interrupt.
沒關系  我只是彈琴放松一下
Not at all. I was just blowing off some steam.
-彈得挺不錯  -謝謝
- You sound good. - ‭Thank you.
有助于保持頭腦清醒  你會彈嗎
Clears the head. You play?
上高中時學過一陣
Oh, I tried to learn in high school,
但后來我決定用更簡單的方法追女孩
but then I decided there were easier ways to get girls.
我希望你有減壓的方法
well, I hope you've got a way to decompress.
人人都需要減壓
Everybody needs something.
你在這適應得怎么樣
How you settling in?
挺好的
Great.
對我來說是向前邁了一大步
Uh, it's -- ‭it's quite a step up for me.
我們很高興有你加入
Well, we're happy to have you.
有其他需要隨時告訴我們  吉米
Just let us know if there's anything else you need, Jimmy.
謝謝  克利福德
Thanks...Cliff.
我也很高興能加入這里
Um, I'm happy to be here.
很好
Great.
我該回去工作了
Uh, better get back to it.
好的  我也該工作了
Yeah, me, too, I suppose.
其實  我在首次信息披露中發現了點東西
Actually, um, ‭I might have found something in the initial disclosures.
-是嗎  -斯韋卡特和考科利不斷提到
- Oh, yeah? - Schweikart and Cokely keep referring to
這是一個"可選的津貼項目"
the "Optional Allowance Program,"
但是我查了很多住戶的合同
but I checked a number of residents' contracts.
所有合同都選擇了這個津貼計劃
Not a single one has opted out, which makes me think
我認為這更像是一個強制性的財務安排
it's more of a mandatory financial arrangement.
你認為這就是他們在提交的材料中所指的
And you're thinking that's the "Failure to state a claim"
"對起訴的申辯"嗎
that they filed in their answer?
他們不斷強調這是可選計劃  是自愿的
They keep saying it's optional, thereby voluntary.
我們可以利用這點來反擊
I think we can counter that
如果入住的前提條件是必須"選擇加入"
if "Opting in" is a requirement for residency,
事實也是如此
which it sure seems to be,
那他們聲稱的"自愿"就站不住腳了
well, their voluntary claims don't hold water.
你這個發現可能意義重大
Might be on to something here.
干得漂亮  吉米
Nice work, Jimmy.
謝謝  克利福德
Thanks, Cliff.
你好
Hola.
你好啊
Hola. Cómo estás?
歡迎光臨  有什么能為您效勞的
Welcome. How can I help you?
我想打聽下價錢
Um, I was hoping to get an estimate.
是我的車
Uh, mi car. Mi coche.
你們可以干車子的活吧
You do cars?
當然可以  沒問題
Sí. Cars. Todo el tiempo.
我想把坐椅的椅面換一下
I-I was hoping ‭to get my seats reupholstered.
跟我出去看一下好嗎
Um, take a look? Mira?
-稍等一下  -好的
- Un momento. - ‭Sí, sí, sí, sí.
謝謝
Gracias.
就是這輛
Yeah.
換點新鮮東西
Thinking something new.
給這個老家伙一點寵愛
Give the old girl a little love.
我很高興做這個工作
但是有這些錢還不如買輛新車
他說你還是留著錢買輛新車比較劃算
He said you should save your money and get a new car.
是嗎  但是我對這輛車有特殊的感情
Yeah? Well, it has a sentimental value.
古董車
Classic car.
他想要什么樣的
椅面想用什么材料
What material do you want?
當然是皮的
Well, I was thinking leather, definitely.
鱷魚皮就不錯
Maybe alligator.
那要花好多錢呢
Señor. Too much money.
是  但我說了  我對這車有感情
Yeah, but like I said, it has a sentimental value.
我覺得奇奇怪怪的皮革跟這車不太配
換點跟車的風格更搭的材料比較好
說服他
他說鱷魚皮跟這輛車不搭
He says, uh, alligator's gonna look all wrong.
便宜點的材料更好
Cheaper might be better.
給我看看你選的
Well, show me what you'd pick.
抱歉  先生
I'm sorry, señor.
我兒子  讓他來幫你  行嗎
My son -- ‭he -- he will help you, okay?
幫他選個材料
別給他推銷貴的了
見到你很高興
Mucho gusto.
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
你找我干什么
Why are you here?
棒球卡
Baseball cards.
我猜  你看到那個開豪車的中年危機男
The way I figure, you saw that mid-life crisis of a vehicle
就明智地決定不和他做生意了
and wisely decided ‭to cut ties with the man,
這我不怪你  因為我也不和他做了
and I don't blame you -- I did, too.
但是你劫了他家
And then you ripped him off.
我相信順走那些棒球卡
And I'm sure those baseball cards
還能從那個蠢貨身上額外撈一筆
looked like an easy way to make a few extra bucks
順便還能給他上一課
off that idiot, teach him a lesson, too.
但是你低估了
But you underestimated
這個人有多么白癡
just how big an idiot you were dealing with.
不  我很清楚
No, I am pretty aware.
好吧  那么你低估了
Well, then, you underestimated
這個人對這些棒球卡片的感情有多深
how attached the man was to those cards --
深到他打給警察報失
so attached he called the police and reported them stolen.
現在警察在到處查
Now they're nosing around.
這好像是你的問題
That sounds like a "you" problem.
不  我覺得更像是我們的問題
No, I think it's very much an "us" problem.
我想我還是碰碰運氣吧
Yeah, I guess I'll just have to take my chances.
不過祝你好運
But good luck to you.
我還希望你能看到我們的困境
You know, I was hoping you'd see our dilemma
做出正確的選擇
and do the right thing.
但我想現在是一個軟硬兼施的情況
But I think what we have here now is a carrot-and-stick situation.
是嗎
Oh, yeah?
這是要來硬的嗎
This is the stick? Hmm?
你來威脅我的家人嗎
You coming here, threatening my family?
你得再強硬些  老東西
'Cause you're gonna need a bigger stick, old man.
我不是要威脅你的家人
I'm not here to threaten your family.
真正的狠角色是屠庫·塞拉曼加
And the name of the stick is Tuco Salamanca.
如果你不照我說的做  恕我直言
Now, you don't play ball, so to speak,
屠庫要是發現了你的第二職業
and Tuco finds out about your little side business.
這夠硬了嗎
That a big enough stick?
不過  我還是更喜歡軟的
However, I prefer the carrot.
我覺得你也會喜歡
I think you will, too.
那要怎么做
And what would that be?
你把棒球卡片還給我
You give me back the baseball cards,
還有一萬美金現鈔
$10,000 in cash,
你還可以凈賺大約
and you net roughly --
大約六萬美金
roughly -- $60,000.
那要如何做到
And how exactly does that work?
歐內斯托
Ernesto.
要出門嗎
Going somewhere?
是的
Yes, we are.
轉彎的時候需要些技巧
She's a little tricky around the corners.
而且  得加高級汽油
So... and you got to go with the premium gas.
我知道這好像是騙人的  但還是有很大不同
I know it seems like a scam, but it makes a huge difference.
我會一周洗一次車
And I would get her washed at least once a week.
還要手工打蠟
And spring for the hand wax.
這透明涂層需要多一層保護
You're gonna want that extra layer of protection for the clear coat.
這車值得最好的保護
She deserves the best.
我會確保拆車廠的伙計們
I'll make sure the boys at the chop shop
對她溫柔一些的
are real gentle with her.
等等  為什么要拆
Wait. W-why?
不
No.
你覺得我會開那輛車嗎
You think I'd be caught dead driving that thing?
那就跟六歲皮條客的校車一樣
It looks like a school bus for 6-year-old pimps.
好了  我們能繼續了嗎
All right, shall we move this along?
阿倫
Aaron.
好  這是基特那張
Okay, there's Jeter.
好的  好的
All right. Okay.
曼托  曼托  這是曼托那張
Mantle. Mantle. There's Mantle.
完事了嗎
‭We good?
是的  好像都在這兒
Uh, yeah, that looks like everyone.
都在  都在這兒了
Yeah, they're here. ‭Looks like everyone's here.
另外一樣
And now the other item.
現在我們的交易正式結束
And now our business is concluded.
我一直在想是不是該向你道歉
You know, I can't help thinking an apology was in order.
又是警察打來的
Uh, it's -- it's the police again.
磯鷂渡并沒有真正回應我們的披露請求
Sandpiper hasn't really responded to our discovery requests.
他們讓我們做了大量文書工作
They've buried us in paperwork,
但沒有任何東西跟這個案子的詳情有關
but nothing actually relevant to the particulars in this case.
意料之中
No real surprise there.
我們也許該要求他們出示銀行記錄
We may have to subpoena their bank records.
謝謝  艾琳  吉米
Thank you, Erin. Jimmy.
客戶那兒處理的怎么樣了
How we doing with client outreach?
我們在等那些傳票的同時
Oh, while we're waiting on those subpoenas,
還應該嘗試從客戶那里
I'm thinking we should try wrangling some of this stuff
獲取文件
from the clients themselves.
他們中大部分人都會保留復印文本
Most of these folks have hard copies of everything
可追溯到埃森豪威爾時代
going back to ‭the Eisenhower administration.
當然  考慮到他們的...
Of course, given some of their, uh...
不一致的組織方式
inconsistent organizational practices,
進展會很緩慢
it's gonna be slow going.
抱歉打斷一下
I'm so sorry to interrupt.
有一位女士  人很好
Uh, this one lady, um, she's sweet,
但是完全聽不見
but, uh, deaf as a doornail.
她把所有的文件都放在  放在
She keeps all of her paperwork in, um, she keeps it --
對不起  抱歉  吉米
I'm sorry. Excuse me, Jimmy.
我需要所有人的手機
I'm gonna need everybody's phone,
鑰匙  還有電子設備
key fobs, and electronics.
查克  歡迎
Chuck. Welcome.
請坐
Please. Have a seat.
不要在意我
Don't mind me.
大家好
Hey, everybody.
抱歉打擾了
Sorry for the interruption.
就當我不在這兒
Just pretend I'm not here.
很高興你能來
Happy to have you.
吉米  我們說到哪兒了
Jimmy, where were we?
對
Uh, yeah.
我正說到...
So, I was saying...
從部分委托人那獲取文件
getting the documents from some of the clients...
他們中的有些人顯然是囤物狂
We definitely have some pack rats.
祝他們好運
God bless 'em.
我那天去拜訪圣達菲磯鷂渡的古斯多夫女士
I was visiting Mrs. Gusdorff at, uh, Sandpiper Santa Fe,
那天下午我都在整理大賣場發放的
and I spent the whole afternoon sorting through just a haystack
成堆的菜譜和半價優惠券
of recipes and half-off coupons from Big Lots.
但整理的成果是這位女士
But now we've got copies of this woman's monthly statements
從1997年3月起的月賬單
going back to march 1997,
因此  盡管這樣有些耗費人力
so it might be a little labor-intensive,
但委托人永遠是我們最好的資源
but our clients will always be our best resource.
此外  他們那還有糖吃
Plus, they have ribbon candy.
吉米
Jimmy.
你好
Hello?
你來干什么
What are you doing here?
我名字就刻在這座樓上
‭My name is on the building.
很高興你能回來
So great to have you here.
如果你需要什么  我就在辦公室
If you need anything, I'll be in my office.
你來干什么
Why are you here?
來親眼見證
To bear witness.
詹姆斯·麥吉爾
James Mcgill.
我是厄門紹特
It's Ehrmantraut.
你的道德觀念還夠靈活嗎
You still morally flexible?
如果是  我有個活兒給你
If so, I might have a job for you.
何時何地
Where and when?
請坐
Take a seat.
沃莫爾德先生  感謝你能前來配合調查
Mr. Wormald, thank you for coming in and talking to us.
當然
Yeah, of course.
我們看了警官在現場
Yeah, we've been looking at the reports
所寫的報告
that the officers took at the scene,
我們有幾個后續的小問題
and we have a few ‭small follow-up questions.
抱歉浪費你的時間  只是常規流程
Sorry to waste your time. Just standard stuff.
沒必要帶律師過來
There's really no need for a lawyer to be here.
我其實是來當他的顧問
I'm here in more of an advisory capacity.
丹只是想有個友善的人在他身邊
Dan just, uh, wanted a friendly face next to him.
我們都很友善啊
‭Well, we're all friendly here.
看看我們  四個朋友
Look at us. Four friends.
我們只是想理清事實
We just want to get the facts straight
以便幫你找回你的財物
so we can, um, help you get your property for you.
其實...沒關系的
Yeah, you know, uh, it's fine.
用不著...
Uh, yeah, there's no need to, uh --
不  這只是常規程序
No, it's just standard procedure.
你知道  警官有時
You know, ‭officers don't always get
也無法把所有的所需信息寫進報告里
all the information we need in their report.
我們只是想抓住偷了你的棒球卡的人
We just want to find the guys who took your baseball cards.
是啊  那...
Yeah, that's, uh...
我叔叔有一張泰·柯布的煙草卡
You know, my uncle ‭had a Ty Cobb tobacco card.
他把那玩意存放在十五厘米厚的玻璃底下
Kept that thing behind six inches of glass
好像是幅名畫一樣
like it was the Mona Lisa or something.
泰·柯布
Wow. Ty Cobb?
告訴他把光線調暗
Tell him to keep the lights low.
就算是人工照明也會釋放一定量的
Even artificial lighting has a certain amount
紫外輻射  那可能會...
of ultraviolet radiation that can, uh, you know...
長遠來看...
over the long term --
你能告訴我們
Um, can you just remind us
你在屋子里存放卡片的準確位置嗎
exactly where you kept your cards in the house?
好的  正如我想說的  那再不是問題了
Yeah, well, uh, as I was trying to say, it's no longer an issue.
我找到它們了
I found them.
你找到卡片了
So you found the cards?
是的
Uh, yep.
我就是想親自過來  告訴你們
I just wanted to come down and tell you, you know, in person.
你找到了
You found them?
在哪  房子周圍嗎
Where? Around the house?
不是  我雇了私家偵探
No. I, uh, I hired a private investigator,
他找到了卡片
and he tracked them down.
是的
So, yeah.
真的嗎  哪兒找到的
Really? So, where were they?
沒關系了  真的
You know, it's fine. It is.
我真的...我不能再打擾你們了
I really -- I ought to get out of your hair.
你們在我身上浪費的時間夠多了
You've wasted enough time on me.
不  不  沒關系  這是我們的工作
No, no, it's -- ‭it's okay. It's our job.
我們只是想弄清真相
We just want to get the facts right
以便幫你結案
so we can help close this case for you.
已經搞定了
It's done.
案子結了
Case closed!
我知道你們有多...
I just -- I know how much, you know,
你們有多少案子需要處理
you guys have on your hands,
殺人犯  搶劫犯  黑幫什么的
like murderers and robbers and gangs and stuff. I --
丹尼  你要不要出去透會氣
Hey, Danny, ‭why don't you get some air?
你去喝點咖啡
You can have some coffee.
我來和警探們說清楚
I'll finish up ‭with the detectives here.
好了  伙計們  我們直說吧
Okay, let's get down to brass tacks here, guys.
我猜你們兩位制服整齊的警官
I'm guessing your two fine uniformed officers
發現了沃莫爾德先生藏東西的據點
found Mr. Wormald's little hidey hole,
所以你們才如此熱心地
and that's why you two are so interested
"幫助"我這位朋友
in "Helping" my friend here.
我明白
I get it.
在踢腳線背后發現藏匿地點
A hiding place in the baseboard --
任何人都會起疑心的
it's gonna make anyone suspicious.
但我保證沒有違法的事
But let me assure you there's nothing illegal going on here.
那他為什么這么緊張
Then why is he so nervous?
因為要我說  流汗就值得懷疑
'cause I must say, the flop sweat is kind of suspect.
我們都有秘密  不是嗎
We all have our secrets, don't we?
又有誰是一塵不染的呢
And who among us is without sin?
但那些罪過不全是犯罪
But those sins aren't all of the criminal variety,
沃莫爾德先生也沒有犯罪
and neither are Mr. Wormald's, okay?
但那是很私密的東西
They are, however, very private.
私密  比如販毒嗎
Private, like drug dealer, maybe?
不  當然不是
No, no!
他一直回避  因為那是個敏感話題
He's being evasive because it's a sensitive subject,
需要小心處理  和執法完全無關
very delicate, and of no concern to law enforcement.
盡管我們想相信你的話
You know, as much as we'd love to, um, take your word for it,
但你說的這些還不夠
we're gonna need a little more than that.
好吧  這都歸結到一起私人糾紛上
All right, well, this all comes down to a personal dispute.
就這樣
That's all.
是沃莫爾德先生
It's -- it's between, um, Mr. Wormald
還有他的藝術贊助人的糾紛
and, uh... his art patron.
-"藝術贊助人"  -沒錯
- "Art patron"? - ‭Yeah.
我的委托人和一個有錢人有一個協議
Uh, my client has an arrangement with a wealthy gentleman
沃莫爾德先生向他提供
for whom Mr. Wormald provides...
藝術品  以此獲得他慷慨的...
art in exchange for ‭this gentleman's generous, uh...
我們稱之為資助
We'll call it patronage.
藝術品  例如繪畫嗎
Art? Like -- like what? Paintings?
更像是電子媒體
It's more like digital media.
電子媒體
Digital media?
他為那個人拍視頻
He made videos for the man.
哪種視頻
What kind of videos?
具有藝術性的私人視頻
Private videos of an artistic nature.
那就是藏在暗道里的東西
That's what was in the hiding place.
就是這樣
That's what it's for.
那么這個藝術贊助人偷了視頻和棒球卡嗎
So, this art patron stole the videos and the baseball cards?
那是個誤會
Well, there was a misunderstanding.
還是叫創意分歧比較好
I mean, uh, ‭call it creative differences.
藝術家都是喜怒無常的
Artists are volatile creatures.
伙計們  這就是情人吵架
Guys, this all comes down to just a lovers' spat, okay?
兩個成年男子鬧翻了
Two consenting adults had a falling out.
常有的事
That happens.
贊助人偷了視頻
And the, uh, "Patron" stole the videos
還有棒球卡  我猜是為了"表明觀點"
and the baseball cards, uh, to "Make a point," I guess.
但關鍵是  都解決了
But the headline here is, it's all settled.
感情修復了
Hearts have mended,
沃莫爾德先生不會起訴
and Mr. Wormald will not be pressing charges.
視頻內容是什么
What was on these videos?
-很私密  -我知道
- They were private. - You've said that.
視頻內容意在
They were videos intended
刺激感官
to titillate the senses.
-好吧  是黃片嗎  -不
- Okay, so porn. - Not -- no.
不是這種
Not as such.
嚴格來說  應該是戀物視頻
Technically, they would be categorized as fetish videos.
但沒有違法內容
But nothing illegal.
就是一個男人  穿戴整齊  我補充一句
Just a man -- a fully clothed man, I might add --
只有他自己
Just all by himself.
沃莫爾德先生穿戴整齊
Just -- just Mr. Wormald fully clothed,
沒錯
yeah.
-就是這樣  -好的
- So... - All right.
所以穿戴整齊的沃莫爾德先生
So, fully clothed Mr. Wormald
在做什么事
by himself doing what?
是啊  在做什么
Yeah, come on, man. What?
"蹲派"
Squat cobbler.
蹲什么玩意兒
What's a s-squat cobbler?
蹲派  你們知道的
Squat cobbler. ‭You know what squat cobbler is.
不  我不知道那是什么
No, I don't -- I don't know what a squat cobbler is.
我也不知道  那是什么
No, me neither. What is it?
你們兩是警察嗎
What? And you two guys are cops?
霍博肯蹲派
Hoboken squat cobbler.
滿月派
Full moon moon-pie.
波士頓奶油派
Boston cream splat.
真的嗎
Seriously?
蹲男"西蒙"
Simple-simon-the-ass-man.
荷蘭蘋果蹲
Dutch apple ass.
伙計們  我說的不是英語嗎
Guys, am I not speaking english here?
蹲派到底是什么
What the hell is a squat cobbler?!
就是一個男人坐在派里
It's when a man sits in pie!
他坐在派里
He sits in a pie!
還來回扭動
And he... he wiggles around.
也許是好樂門蛋黃醬
Maybe it's like Hellmann's mayonnaise.
落基山以西有不同的叫法
It has a different name west of the Rockies.
我也不知道  但嚴格來說
I don't know. But, uh, technically,
他是邊哭邊蹲的
He does a crybaby squat, so there's tears,
所以看起來更專業
which makes it more specialized.
不是所有蹲派者都要哭的
Not all pie sitters cry.
但我要說的是
But I'm gonna tell you something.
這家伙一哭起來
This guy is a regular Julianne Moore
演得比朱麗安·摩爾還棒
once he gets ‭the waterworks cranked up.
派
Pies?
比如蘋果派嗎
What? Like apple?
伙計  不是我拍的好嗎
Guys, I'm not ‭the filmmaker here, all right?
有香蕉奶油  桃子
Banana cream. I -- uh, peach.
哦對  還要穿道具服裝
Oh, and there -- ‭and there is a costume involved.
你忽悠我們呢
You got to be shitting us.
是啊  隨便你們信不信
Yeah, like I would make this up.
大千世界無奇不有  兄弟
Hey, the world is ‭a rich tapestry, my friends.
不過相信我
But trust me on this.
你們不會想看的
You don't want to see it.
所以  沒事了  是吧
So, uh, we're good, right?
是  沒問題了
Yeah. Great.
不過  還有一個小隱患  要善后
There is, however, one little, tiny hanging chad.
什么  什么隱患
Well, what? What chad?
你得拍一個視頻
You're gonna have to make a video.
等等等等
wait. Wait.
他是把餡餅吃了還是坐在餡餅里
So he eats the pies or just sits in them?
都有  想要什么有什么
Both. Whatever you want.
哪個先來
Which comes first?
隨便他選
Uh, it's dealer's choice.
這時候就該上哭戲了  是吧
That's where the crying comes in, right?
哭戲是必須的
That's a safe bet.
你到底是怎么想出這主意的
How the hell ‭did you come up with that?
就是給我一百年
If you gave me a million years,
我也想不出這玩意
I still would not have come up with that.
靈感女神
The muse.
我說出了她的想法
She speaks through me.
我不過是區區傳話筒
I am but a humble vessel.
他們信了嗎
And they bought it?
信了
Yeah.
我也聽說過一些很離譜讓人難以相信的情節
I've heard some far-out scenarios used to sow doubt,
但這絕對是最扯淡[贏得蛋糕]的
but this definitely takes the cake.
金  金  金
Kim, Kim, Kim.
-知道啦是"餡餅"  -對
- Takes the pie. ‭- Yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
我現在應該跳樓謝罪
I should just jump off the roof right now.
對啊  你是該自責
Yeah, you should feel bad about yourself.
天哪  你可真能謅
Jesus, can you tell a story.
我覺得其實是那視頻讓他們信了
Well, to be fair, I think it was the video that clinched it.
什么視頻
What video?
等等  你們真的拍了一個視頻
Wait, wait. You -- ‭you actually made a video?
不得不說  到最后  老丹還挺入戲的
I got to say, in the end, Ol' Dan really committed.
那眼淚把我都打動了
I believed the tears.
這個是剩下的道具  多出來的
Um, this is a leftover prop. It was extra.
我不確定我們要拍幾條  就多買了些
I wasn't sure how many takes we would need, so I over-bought,
不過我保證  絕對沒被屁股坐過
But I promise you, ‭untouched by human buttocks.
你偽造證據
You fabricated evidence?
我就拍了個視頻
I made a video.
算不上證據
Not exactly evidence.
你用它來為委托人脫罪
You used it to exonerate a client.
你用偽造的證據為委托人脫罪
You used falsified evidence to exonerate a client.
你這是鉆牛角尖
Mm, I think you're splitting hairs.
我沒有鉆牛角尖
I'm not splitting hairs.
萬一戴維斯梅因律所發現你偽造證據怎么辦
What if Davis & Main find out you faked evidence?
他不是戴維斯梅因律所的客戶
It wasn't a Davis & Main client.
這不是什么案子  無償的
It was some nothing, little pro-bono thing.
與工作無關  完全是  我的私事
It was off the clock. It was, uh, totally my own thing.
為什么
Why?
你為什么要冒丟工作的風險
Why would you risk the best job you've ever had
就為了一個無償服務的案子
for some pro-bono case?
我是幫朋友的忙
I was doing a favor for a friend.
冒著被取消律師資格的風險  真是良友
Risking disbarment? That's -- that's some friend.
沒事的  事情解決了
It's fine! It -- it worked out.
戴維斯梅因律所并不知情
Davis & Main are none the wiser.
吉米  你這是在玩火
Jimmy, ‭you're playing with fire here.
那天晚上那個混蛋肯
I didn't see you complaining
幫我們付酒單的時候  我可沒見你抱怨
when, um, Ken the douchebag paid our bar bill the other night.
是吧  那也有點違反規定了吧
No, that was a little bit of rule breaking right there.
要是我沒記錯  你還挺喜歡的
And if I remember correctly, you liked it.
很喜歡
A lot.
這完全不是一回事
That is so not the same thing.
怎么不是一回事  有什么區別
How? What's the difference?
那與工作無關
That had nothing to do with work.
而且我們就是在胡鬧
And we were just -- just screwing around.
但是這個
This?
偽造證據
Fabricating evidence.
吉米  這真的可能會害了你
Jimmy, ‭this could really hurt you.
如果他們發現了  如果你被抓
If they find out, if you get caught --
這  他們永遠不會發現的
It -- they're never gonna find out.
你不是吧
Seriously?
這話說得就跟那些蠢蛋罪犯一模一樣
You sound like every dumb criminal out there.
如果你再這么干  他們遲早會發現
If you keep this up, they will find out.
你圖什么  吉米
For what, Jimmy? ‭
到底為了什么
What is the point?
我不想再看到你做這種事情
I cannot hear ‭about this sort of thing.
一次也不行了  聽到了嗎
Ever again. Okay?
我認真的  吉米
I mean it, Jimmy.
不會再有了
You won't.
非常歡迎愛好者加入字幕組一起翻譯海外影視劇
最新美劇下載請登錄字幕組網站
掃描左邊二維碼關注我們的微信號
或搜索微信號: ustvboom